Real voices. Real survival. Real protection.
So, the fire in our home occurred
on the 26th of January of this year.
Basically, it was just
another normal day where myself
like obviously along with my
my husband like other
couples taking care of our
home and the daily affairs.
Um, before going to bed
we placed our laundry in
the tumble dryer, and went to bed as
usual. Suddenly,
something just woke me up.
I honestly did not smell
any smoke or any
sounds. I just suddenly woke up
and I saw the smoke
and immediately became aware
that this was a case involving fire.
Obviously, I immediately woke up
my husband and the children.
We saw the fire coming out
out from the kitchen area
where there is the tumble dryer.
The tumble dryer was on fire obviously.
The fault was from the tumble dryer,
it turned on fire because there
is a part within that was not
functioning well,
and this part obviously failed
to cutoff during heat
and caused the fire.
I would like to add that
the tumble dryer wasn't our
fault or negligence from
our end.
We obviously took care
and repaired the tumble dryer
a few days before,
not even a month prior.
It was an appliance which
we haven't bought years ago,
but an appliance bought
much less than two years.
Obviously the first thing one
does is to fix the matter,
right, and you take
from the technician.
We are not knowledgeable
in such areas,
therefore you obviously
turn to those who have a better understanding.
Following that, the tumble dryer
was working as normal,
but then, the problem occurred
concerning the part which we had fixed.
A major part of our home that
endured damage is the kitchen area,
but obviously, the damage affected
the entire home.
From the kitchen, the fire was spreading
into the living room.
The air-condition and other equipment
were damaged
In reality, the only thing which we managed
to save from the entire home
are this sofa that we are sitting on
and the television.
Obviously, since we called
the first responders
and the fire engines arrived,
and these sorts of things,
and they need to extinguish the fire.
Obviously, things got damaged,
but we were not injured thanks God,
especially since we received
immediate assistance
thanks to the fire brigade
Who in a very short period
they arrived at our door step,
in less than 7 minutes.
But obviously,
you are affected from an emotionally.
The fact that my first instinct,
I couldn't find my daughter,
feel the matter as taking a lot of time.
Our daughter is 5 years old,
and so the risk of being entrapped
in the smoke or fire is higher,
and breathing would become even
more difficult leading to a moment
of panic.
We received care concerning
emotional damage,
we went for therapy and received
psychological care as we have
been guided.
So, thanks God,
we received the aftercare
which helped us to move forward.
Obviously, there would still be
the effects of what occurred,
which involves nightmares and wake
up in shock and memories of what
took place. But obviously, live goes on.
Financially this was certainly a hit,
we have been here only for 6 months
and everything was still new.
So, we were already within a financial
expense involving the moving process.
Obviously, the incident occurred,
and the matter became even bigger.
When we moved in,
there wasn't much work which
we required to do, but,
due to the fire, our expenses got bigger,
almost tripled.
Something which I highly
recommend is to take all the necessary precautions,
and to have the required emergency
equipment such as fire extinguishers,
fire blankets, fire alarms.
These are things that if myself
and my family already had in place,
we would have avoided some
of the problems that occurred.
For example, if there would be
smoke, and the fire alarm would go off,
obviously we would have
called for help earlier.
These are things that I
believe are necessary
as other necessary things
that one has in the kitchen
and their daily lives.
Nowadays, if you had to come
over to our home,
you will find these
in all the rooms,
including fire extinguishers and fire blanket.
This experience helped
us to learn.
Those who are watching this interview,
my advice is to never wait
for an accident to occur
God forbid before acting.
Following this interview,
these should be part of your plan.
Nowadays, thanks God,
our position is much better.
We came back to our home after 4
months and obviously these
were 4 months of hard times.
My husband also had to take
some time off from his work
in order to accelerate the process
to move in as soon as possible.
We turned this place in shell form,
including the bathrooms.
Obviously you then need to start again
from the beginning which
takes some time.
Emotionally speaking,
I myself am in a much better state.
As I told you earlier, we
received the necessary care,
psychological help and
therapy that we needed.
Our children, thanks God,
we tried to present the matter
from a positive side.
For them the fire brigade and police
are their heroes,
particularly since they treated them so well
on the day, that for them
we were special since we encountered these heroes.
The fire man gathered some items
and managed to save some items
which my kids remember
more than the fire itself.
My daughter remembers the police
in particular who wrapped here
in a scarf because we took
her out in her underwear.
From this negative experience,
there is still something positive
which our children took.
Financially, obviously we need to recover
from the hit that we faced.
We both continued with our routines now,
and when you are careful
with your expenses,
obviously you start rebuilding your life.